# **Justin Lee**

LinkedIn | GitHub | justin-huiyun-lee.com

Location: Cupertino, California, United States Email: justin.huiyun.lee@gmail.com | Mobile: 925-660-5548

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

I am a highly skilled full stack and systems developer with **4+ years of experience** in **Rustlang, C++, and C**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **Next.js, Tailwindcss, and Node.js** and experience with REST APIs and MVC frameworks.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : Rustlang, C++, C, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, LaTeX

**Technologies**: Next.js, TailwindCSS, Prisma, Drizzle ORM

**Tools** : Neovim, Alacritty, Tmux, Debian, Git/Github, Figma

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Stanford Science Small Groups Researcher**

Jan 2023 - May 2023

- Worked with a Stanford PhD Student on neural networks and AI research
- Established hypotheses and conducted research regarding curiosity driven learning, self supervised learning, and deep neural networks
- Presented research in front of PhDs with expertise across multiple disciplines.

## Mobile App Development Internship at OurDate

August 2023 – November 2023

- Programmed auto scheduling features using JavaScript and Google API
- · Designed website and app home pages using Figma

### Study Buddy Mentor

Aug 2022 – Feb 2023

- Taught and mentored international, and/or under-performing, students from diverse backgrounds
- Taught many subjects, including Computer Science, Biology, English, Math, and History

# **PROJECTS**

# **Liquid Neural Network Research Project**

Rust-lang, Computer Architecture

Source Code

- Utilized Rust-lang, Computer Arhitecture Knowledge, Systems Programming, and knowledge of high-level Mathematics to design and develop memory and performance optimizations, enabling cheaper and more efficient development of machine learning models.
- Contacted various professors and Ph.D students across multifarious universities for support on the project.

# **ChoppingBoard - AI Short Content Creator**

React.js, JavaScript, TailwindCSS, FFMPEG

Source Code

- Utilized React.js, TailwindCSS, JavaScript, and FFMPEG to design and develop a website
  enabling users to cut video files based on user-inputted timestamps.
- Employed JavaScript and FFMPEG to re-encode video files with AI generated subtitles.
- Utilized **React.js and TailwindCSS** to implement a responsive design, ensuring seamless compatibility of the website across various screen sizes.
- Deployed on GitHub pages via GitHub Actions

## **AfterLife - Java Game Project**

Java, Git

Source Code

- Designed and Developed a Java Application made with the Swing library
- Leveraged **Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)** principles to create reusable classes and functions, enabling their application in diverse scenarios.

# **EDUCATION**

## **Monta Vista High School**

Cupertino, California, United States